Guide to the Matt Phillips Sketchbooks, 1962-2008 M1046
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Matt Phillips Sketchbooks, 1962-2008
M1046
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
6.0 Linear feet 141 volumes
Collection contains 141 sketchbooks produced by artist Matt Phillips between 1962 and 2009.
Phillips, Matt, 1927-
Arrangement Note
The sketchbooks are arranged chronologically, except for recent acquisitions which are filed at the end.
Biography
Best known for his monotype work, Phillips was born in New York City in 1927. He studied at the University of Chicago (MA 1952) and attended Stanford 1952-1954. He later traveled in Europe and taught at Pennsylvania State University.
Provenance
Purchased, 1999 (118 v.); gift of Matt Phillips, 1999 (2 v.); purchased, 2000 (2 v.), gift, 2000 (1 v.); purchased, 2001 (2 v.); purchased, 2002 (2 v.); purchased, 2003 (6 v.); purchaed, 2006 (1 v.); purchased, 2007 (4 v.); purchased, 2009 (1 v.)
1999-076, 1999-319, 1999-321, 2000-009, 2000-185, 2001-030, 2002-070,, 2003-004, 2003-123, 2003-143, 2003-326, 2006-065, 2007-159, 2007-265, 2009-172
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
American art--20th century.; Sketchbooks.
- [Sketchbook] 1, 1962 Aug.; Sketchbook No. 1; 70 leaves: majority filled, watercolor and pencil, 13.5 x 10.1. one loose leaf, notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 1, Volume 1)
- [Sketchbook] 2: Matt Phillips 3 rue du Midy, Nevilly Sur/Seine, France, 3/10, 1963?; Sketchbook No. 2; 75 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10 x 13.9. Leaves filled. notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 1, Volume 2)
  France
- [Sketchbook] 3: France, 1963; Sketchbook No. 3; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10 x 14. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 1, Volume 3)
- [Sketchbook] 4: 1963 Paris, Vienna etc., Sketchbook No. 4; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10 x 14.1. Majority of leaves filled. Notes on final 3 leaves and inside final board (Box 1, Volume 4)
  Paris (France); Vienna
- [Sketchbook] 5: "Seville 1963" on first leaf, Sketchbook No. 5; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.9. Majority of leaves filled. Notes on final leaf (Box 1, Volume 5)
  Sevilla (Spain)
- [Sketchbook] 6: Paris '63 Spring, 1963 spring; Sketchbook No. 6; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10 x 14. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaves and inside final board. One loose photograph (Box 1, Volume 6)
  Paris (France)
- [Sketchbook] 7: Paris [???] Oct., 1964, 1964 Oct.; Sketchbook No. 7; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 14.1. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 1, Volume 7)
- [Sketchbook] Paris '63 or '64 (?), 1963-1964; 70, 3 leaves filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 14 x 9.9. (Box 1, Volume 8)
- [Sketchbook] Frank Lloyd Wright - Synagogue, Elkins Park, Pa. & [???], 1963 or 1964; 65 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10 x 14. Three-quarters of leaves blank. Notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 1, Volume 9)
  Elkins Park (Pennsylvania)
- [Sketchbook] #7: 1964-65 Phillips, 1964-1965; Sketchbook No. #7; 40 leaves: ink drawings, 13 x 18.4. Majority of leaves blank. (Box 1, Volume 10)
- [Sketchbook] 8: Beaches -N.Y. 1965 & Sandy 1968, 1965 & 1968; Sketchbook No. 8; 75 leaves: pencil, ink, watercolor, 10.3 x 14. Leaves filled. (Box 1, Volume 11)
  New York
- [Sketchbook] 9, ca. 1965; Sketchbook No. 9; 75 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.5 x 13.5. Leaves filled. Notes on final 6 leaves (Box 1, Volume 12)
- [Sketchbook] 10: 1966 [?] -Beach/Camping/Sandy, Sketchbook No. 10; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.5 x 13.5. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaf (Box 1, Volume 13)
- [Sketchbook] 11: 3/10, 1967 July; Sketchbook No. 11; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 14. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 1, Volume 14)
- [Sketchbook] 12, 1967 July; Sketchbook No. 12; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.9. Leaves filled. Notes inside back board (Box 1, Volume 15)
- [Sketchbook] 13: Venice, '67, 1967; Sketchbook No. 13; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.1 x 13.9. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 1, Volume 16)
  Venice (Italy)
- [Sketchbook] S.S. Winter 1967: Began with Sandy, Winter, 1967, 1967 Winter; 60 leaves: watercolor & pencil, 16.5 x 14. Majority of leaves blank. (Box 2, Volume 17)
- [Sketchbook] #4 (See Small 14): Around 1968, Phillips, Sketchbook No. #14; 70, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 14 x 21.6. Notes inside final board (Box 2, Volume 18)
- [Sketchbook] 14: Miscellaneous: Beach, Saratoga, Sandy, N.Y., etc., 1968 Aug.; Sketchbook No. 14; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 14.1. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 2, Volume 19)
- [Sketchbook] 15: Mat Phillips Still Lifes, 1968 Aug.; Sketchbook No. 15; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.5. (Box 2, Volume 20)
- [Sketchbook] Sandy, ca. 1968; 25 leaves: colored pencil drawings, 22 x 24.5. One-third of leaves blank. (Box 2, Volume 21)
- [Sketchbook] 17: Domestic Scenes 4/69, 1969 April; Sketchbook No. 17; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.5. Leaves filled. (Box 2, Volume 22)
- [Sketchbook] 18: N.Y. Feb., 1969, 1969 Feb.; Sketchbook No. 18; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.4 x 13.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 2, Volume 23)
- [Sketchbook] 21: July 1969 - N.Y. Beaches, 1969 July; Sketchbook No. 21; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.5. (Box 2, Volume 24)
- [Sketchbook] 20: Aug. '69 Miscellaneous, 1969 Aug.; Sketchbook No. 20; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil, ink and watercolor, 10.4 x 13.5. notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 2, Volume 25)
- [Sketchbook] 16: Around the House Sept. - 1969, 1969 Sept.; Sketchbook No. 16; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.4 x 14. One half of leaves blank. ink drawing signed "Sandy" on final leaf. (Box 2, Volume 26)
- [Sketchbook] 19: Miscellaneous Oct. 24 '69, Beach N.Y. 1974 Calif., 1969 Oct. & 1974; Sketchbook No. 19; 70 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.5. Three-quarters of leaves filled. Notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 2, Volume 27)
- [Sketchbook] 37: Life Drawing Bard, Fall '69, fall '70-spring '73, 1969-1973; Sketchbook No. 37; 80 leaves: pencil, 10.3 x 13.4. Leaves filled. (Box 2, Volume 28)
- [Sketchbook] 35: Local Landscapes '69, 1969; Sketchbook No. 35; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.4. Three-quarters of leaves blank. maps on final 2 leaves (Box 2, Volume 29)
- [Sketchbook] 22: Europe 1970 Matt Phillips London Jan. '70, 1970 Jan.; Sketchbook No. 22; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.5. Leaves filled. Notes on final 2 leaves and inside back board (Box 2, Volume 30)
- [Sketchbook] 23: Malaga Feb 23 '70, 1970 Feb.; Sketchbook No. 23; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.3. Three-quarters of leaves filled. Notes on final leaf (torn) and inside back board (Box 2, Volume 31)
- [Sketchbook] 32: Morocco 3/4/70, 1970 March; Sketchbook No. 32; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.3. notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 3, Volume 32)
- [Sketchbook] 1970 Granada Alhambra: Granada Ranch, '70 (Alhambra), 45, majority filled leaves: ink and watercolor, 18.5 x 24.5. faint notes on inside of back board. some moisture damage (Box 3, Volume 33)
- [Sketchbook] 36: Paris Feb., 1970, 1970 Feb.; Sketchbook No. 36; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.4. Leaves filled. Notes on final 2 leaves and inside final board (Box 3, Volume 34)
- [Sketchbook] 31: Marrakesh 3/10/70, 1970 March; Sketchbook No. 31; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.3. notes inside back board (Box 3, Volume 35)
- [Sketchbook] 25: Paris April 1 '70, 1970 April; Sketchbook No. 25; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.3. notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 3, Volume 36)
- [Sketchbook] 33: Greece 4/14/70, 1970 April; Sketchbook No. 33; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.4. notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 3, Volume 37)
- [Sketchbook] Paris 1970: Sketches: Paris -1970 Sandy, etc. -early '71, 76, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 21.5 x 28. notes on final lf. and notes inside final board (Box 3, Volume 38)
- [Sketchbook] Greece 1970(?): Greece 1970(?), 75, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 14.2 x 21.8. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 3, Volume 39)
- [Sketchbook] 24: Paris June 12, 1970 Rooftops, 1970 June; Sketchbook No. 24; 80 leaves: pencil, 10.2 x 13.3. Three-quarter of leaves blank. notes inside back board (Box 3, Volume 40)
- [Sketchbook] Feb. 1971 S.S.: Feb. 1971, 1971 Feb.; 75, all filled leaves: pencil, colored pencil, ink??, 13.5 x 20. notes on final leaf (Box 3, Volume 41)
- [Sketchbook] 26: S.S. & Joshua 4/71, 1971 April; Sketchbook No. 26; 80 leaves: pencil, colored pencil, watercolor and pastels?, 10.1 x 14. Three-quarters of leaves filled. (Box 3, Volume 42)
- [Sketchbook] 34: Beaches 7/71, 1971 July; Sketchbook No. 34; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 14.1. (Box 3, Volume 43)
- 1972 Beaches [Sketchbook]: Matt Phillips, Studies - Beach. Variations, etc. Began -1/15/72, 45 leaves: ink, charcoal and pencil, 16 x 24. Four leaves loose, two-thirds blank. (Box 4, Volume 44)
- [Sketchbook] 28: N.Y. Beach Scenes Aug. 1972, 1972 Aug.; Sketchbook No. 28; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.5. (Box 4, Volume 45)
- [Sketchbook] 27: Miscellaneous 1972 N.Y., Spring / Summer and Dec. 1973 N.Y., 1972 & 1973; Sketchbook No. 27; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 4, Volume 46)
- [Sketchbook] 38: Landscapes Spring 1973, & Beaches June 1973, 1973 spring; Sketchbook No. 38; 80 leaves: pencil, pen and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.5. One half of leaves blank. (Box 4, Volume 47)
- [Sketchbook] 29: Interiors with [???] Spring '73, 1973 spring; Sketchbook No. 29; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.5. One half of leaves blank. Notes inside back board (Box 4, Volume 48)
- [Sketchbook] 30: Miscellaneous Summer '73, 1973 summer; Sketchbook No. 30; 80 leaves: pen, pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 14.1. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 4, Volume 49)
- [Sketchbook] 39: Provincetown Sept. 1973, Beaches & Ports & Dunes, 1973 Sept.; Sketchbook No. 39; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.4 x 13.5. notes on final 2 leaves and inside back board (Box 4, Volume 50)
- [Sketchbook] 40: FAIR -1974, SUMMER, Sketchbook No. 40; 75 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.5 x 13.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaves (Box 4, Volume 51)
- [Sketchbook] 41: Mexico -1974, Evocations, Sketchbook No. 41; 75 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.5 x 13.5. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 4, Volume 52)
- [Sketchbook] 42: Mexico 1974 March #2, Impressions of Markets, Parks, Streets, etc., Sketchbook No. 42; 75, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.4 x 13.4. notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 4, Volume 53)
- [Sketchbook] 43: Mexico BK. #3 1974 Patzcuaro, etc., Sketchbook No. 43; 80 leaves: pencil, 10.4 x 13.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 4, Volume 54)
- [Sketchbook] 1975 S.S.: Phillips 5/75, 50 leaves: charcoal and pencil, 27.5 x 21. Leaves two-thirds filled. "Car 1972" from inside back board. (Box 4, Volume 55)
- [Sketchbook] 44: Phillips 1975, [Spring crossed out] / Summer, 1975 summer; Sketchbook No. 44; 70, 1/2 blank leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 14.2. notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 4, Volume 56)
- [Sketchbook] 45: Mexico Jan. 4 1976 to Jan. 15 Guatemala, 1976 Jan.; Sketchbook No. 45; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.4 x 13.3. notes on final 3 leaves and inside back board (Box 4, Volume 57)
- [Sketchbook] 46: Guatemala 1976, Jan. 16, Sketchbook No. 46; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.5 x 13.5. notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 5, Volume 58)
- [Sketchbook] 47: New York City March 1976, 1976 March; Sketchbook No. 47; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.4. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 5, Volume 59)
- [Sketchbook] A: Sept. 25 - first of San [???] New York, New York, Broadway, 1977 Apr.; Sketchbook No. A; 80 leaves: pencil, 10.2 x 13.3. Three-quarters of leaves filled. Notes on final 13 leaves and inside back board (Box 5, Volume 60)
- [Sketchbook] B: Sandy - [???] Table 1977-78, 1977-1978; Sketchbook No. B; 60 leaves: pencil, ink, some watercolor, 11.2 x 16. One half of leaves blank. (Box 5, Volume 61)
- [Sketchbook] 1977: June 1977, ? Chicago S.F. Santa Monica N.Y., Sketchbook No. 1977; 140 leaves: pencil, 10.5 x 15.3. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 3 leaves and inside final board (Box 5, Volume 62)
- [Sketchbook] 50: Istanbul #2, Matt Phillips, Bard College, Annandale-On-Hudson, N.Y. 12504, U.S.A, 1978 June 22; Sketchbook No. 50; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.4. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 5, Volume 63)
  Istanbul
- [Sketchbook] 48: Paris! 7/22/78, 1978 July; Sketchbook No. 48; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.3 x 13.3. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 3 leaves and inside back board (Box 5, Volume 64)
- [Sketchbook] 49: Italy - July-1978, Hotel Isa, via Cicerone 35, 1978 July; Sketchbook No. 49; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 13.4. One half of leaves blank. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 5, Volume 65)
- [Sketchbook] 50: At the Table 1978 1979, Sketchbook No. 50; 65, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 11 x 16. notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 5, Volume 66)
- [Sketchbook] C: Nov '79 Miscellaneous Including S.S. with Joshua, 1979 Nov.; Sketchbook No. C; 70 leaves: pencil, 10.1 x 14. Leaves two-thirds blank, many loose leaves, notes inside final board (Box 5, Volume 67)
- [Sketchbook] C.A. - S.F. 1980:, 80, majority filled leaves: pencil, 15 x 21.2. Notes on final leaf (Box 5, Volume 68)
- [Sketchbook] 51: San Francisco feb - 1980, Mexico May 19 - 80, 1980 Feb. & 1980 May; Sketchbook No. 51; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14. Three-quarters of leaves filled. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 5, Volume 69)
- [Sketchbook] 52: Berkeley San Francisco 1/2/3/80, 1980; Sketchbook No. 52; 50 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 9.9 x 15.9. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 5, Volume 70)
- [Sketchbook] 53: Marrakech June 16 -1981, Sketchbook No. 53; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14.1. notes on final leaf, notes and calendar inside final board (Box 6, Volume 71)
- [Sketchbook] 54: Fes June 25 - 1981, 1981 June; Sketchbook No. 54; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14. One half of leaves blank. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 6, Volume 72)
- [Sketchbook] 55: Paris - July 5 -81, 1981 July; Sketchbook No. 55; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 4 leaves and inside back board (Box 6, Volume 73)
- [Sketchbook] 55 (?): Begun N.Y. Aug. 1982 5th Ave. [????], 1982 Aug.; Sketchbook No. 55 (?); 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 6, Volume 74)
- [Sketchbook] 56: S. Spain / Morocco July 15 - '83, 1983 July; Sketchbook No. 56; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 14. One half of leaves blank. Notes on final leaf and inside final board (Box 6, Volume 75)
- [Sketchbook] 57: Summer - 1984, London - June 24, Wales - June 25-29, 1984 summer; Sketchbook No. 57; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14.1. notes and calendar on final leaves, notes inside final board (Box 6, Volume 76)
- [Sketchbook] 58: Barcelona July 10 - 1984, 1984 July; Sketchbook No. 58; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 14. One half of leaves blank. Notes and calendar on final leaf + loose museum stub and business card (Box 6, Volume 77)
- [Sketchbook] 59: Miscellaneous 1985, Sketchbook No. 59; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 14. Leaves two-thirds blank. Notes inside final board (Box 6, Volume 78)
  Scope and Contents note
  a) Wash. D.C. Feb. 15-6 -- b) N.Y. St. Patrick's Day March 16
- [Sketchbook] 60: Moroccan Trip July 11 -'86, 1986 July; Sketchbook No. 60; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14.1. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 2 leaves and inside back board (Box 6, Volume 79)
- [Sketchbook] 61: Moroccan Voyage, 1986 July; Sketchbook No. 61; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14.1. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaf (Box 6, Volume 80)
- [Sketchbook] Paris July 8, 1986: Paris July 8, 1986, 1986 July; 80 leaves: pencil, 13 x 10. Leaves two-thirds blank. Notes on final leaf and back board (Box 6, Volume 81)
- [Sketchbook] 62: July 13, 1987 en route Chaoeun, Morocco, 1987 July; Sketchbook No. 62; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14.1. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 6, Volume 82)
- [Sketchbook] 63: N.Y. Madrid, 1987 July; Sketchbook No. 63; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.6 x 14.1. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 3 leaves and inside final board (Box 6, Volume 83)
  New York; Madrid
- [Sketchbook] F: San Francisco, Matt Phillips Oct. 20, 1987, 1987 Oct.; Sketchbook No. F; 150 leaves: pencil and colored pencil, 15.3 x 10.1. Leaves filled. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 6, Volume 84)
- [Sketchbook] N.Y. Sept. 1988: N.Y., 1988 Sept. 12 - 14; 20 leaves: pencil, 10.2 x 15.2. Leaves filled. (Box 7, Volume 85)
- [Sketchbook], 1989 Mar. 14; 1 v.: pencil, pencil & watercolor. Leaves filled. (Box 7, Volume 86)
- [Sketchbook] Paris, June 27 -1989: Paris, June 27 -1989, 1989 June; 50, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 16 x 12. Notes on final leaf. June calendar on inside of back board (Box 7, Volume 87)
- [Sketchbook] Santa Monica June 1989 and May 23 1998, June '89:, 1989 June; 1998 May; 24, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.2 x 15.2. (Box 7, Volume 88)
- [Sketchbook] 63: Portugal, 1989 July 3; Sketchbook No. 63; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 15.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 7, Volume 89)
- [Sketchbook] 64: Morocco Encore! July 12, 1989, 1989 July; Sketchbook No. 64; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 15.5. notes on final leaf, calendar inside back board (Box 7, Volume 90)
- [Sketchbook], 1989 Aug. 18; 20 leaves: pencil, 10.2 x 15.2. One half of leaves blank. Notes on back board (Box 7, Volume 91)
- [Sketchbook] # See f/G [could also be # See 8/G]: S.F. Oct. 1989, 1989 Oct.; 70 leaves: pencil, 14 x 21.8. One half of leaves blank. Notes inside final board (Box 7, Volume 92)
- [Sketchbook], 1990s; 24, majority filled leaves: pencil, 15.2 x 10.1. notes inside final board., first leaf reads "Berkeley -Telegraph & [????]" (Box 7, Volume 93)
- [Sketchbook] M: Wash. D.C. March 16 -'90, N.Y. City April 10 -'92, Chicago April 15 '92, 1990 March; 1992 April; Sketchbook No. M; 50 leaves: pencil, 14.7 x 9.5. One half of leaves blank. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 7, Volume 94)
- [Sketchbook] D: N.Y. City, 1990 Apr. 30; Sketchbook No. D; 20 leaves: pencil, 10 x 15.2. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes inside final board (Box 7, Volume 95)
- [Sketchbook] G: In and Around S.F. 10/1/90 - 4/91, 1990-1991; Sketchbook No. G; 70, majority filled leaves: pencil, 11 x 15.5. Notes on final leaf (Box 7, Volume 96)
- [Sketchbook] N.Y., Santa Fe, Etc., 1991; 50, majority filled leaves: pencil, 18.8 x 13.2. first leaf reads "NY. Oct 30 - '91", notes on final 3 leaves (Box 8, Volume 97)
  New York; Santa Fe
- [Sketchbook] 1991 Calif.:, 24 leaves: pencil, 10.2 x 15.3. Leaves filled. N (Box 8, Volume 98)
- [Sketchbook]: first drawing dated 3/2/91, 1991 March; 80, majority blank (4 sketches) leaves: pencil, 9 x 12.3. (Box 8, Volume 99)
- [Sketchbook] 65: N.Y., Etc., 1991 May 12 - 18; Sketchbook No. 65; 80 leaves: pencil, 11 x 15.5. One half of leaves blank. (Box 8, Volume 100)
- [Sketchbook]: first drawing dated Sept. 1, 1991, 1991 Sept.; 100, majority blank leaves: pencil, 7.7 x 12.8. (Box 8, Volume 101)
- [Sketchbook], 1992 March; 50 leaves: charcoal, 27.5 x 21. Leaves two-thirds blank. (Box 8, Volume 102)
- [Sketchbook] 68: Paris Nov. 30 -'92, 1992 Nov.; Sketchbook No. 68; 55 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 12.9 x 12.9. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaf (Box 8, Volume 103)
- [Sketchbook] 66: Egypt Dec. 3 -'92, 1992 Dec.; Sketchbook No. 66; 80, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 15.5. loose photo inserted, calendar inside front board, notes on final leaf and inside back board (Box 8, Volume 104)
- [Sketchbook] 67: Egypt II + Israel Dec. 19 - '92, [calendar], 1992 Dec.; Sketchbook No. 67; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 11 x 15.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final leaves and board (Box 8, Volume 105)
- [Sketchbook] March 1994 Yucatan: Yucatan March 4, 1994 [with calendar], 1994 March; 65 leaves: pencil, 11 x 15.5. Leaves two-thirds blank. Notes on final leaves and inside final board (Box 8, Volume 106)
- [Sketchbook]: Tassajara, a zen retreat, 1994 May 9; 1 v.: pencil, 25 x 22. Leaves filled. (Box 8, Volume 107)
- [Sketchbook] 69: March 13, 1995 Mexico, 1995 March; Sketchbook No. 69; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 15.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 6 leaves, calendar inside back board (Box 8, Volume 108)
- [Sketchbook] N.Y., 1995 June 25; 25 leaves: pencil, 10.2 x 15.2. One half of leaves blank. (Box 8, Volume 109)
- [Sketchbook], 1995 July 4; 1 v.: pencil, 15x21.5. Leaves half filled + photograph of Tassajara Zen Center (postcard) (Box 9, Volume 110)
- [Sketchbook] Sept. 1995 Diary Montana: Idaho Falls + Montana, Sept. 17-25 1995, 1995 Sept.; 90, majority filled leaves: pencil, 11 x 15.5. notes throughout, notes on final leaves, calendar on final leaf (Box 9, Volume 111)
- [Sketchbook] N.Y., [1996?] Nov. 26; 20 leaves: pencil, 10.2 x 15.2. One half of leaves blank. (Box 9, Volume 112)
- [Sketchbook] 70: Montana March 11, 1996, 1996 March; Sketchbook No. 70; 60, majority filled leaves: pencil and watercolor, 11 x 15.6. notes and calendar on final leaves, notes inside final board (Box 9, Volume 113)
- [Sketchbook] 71: Feb. 5 -18 1997 Trip from S.F. to Guatemala, 1997 Feb.; Sketchbook No. 71; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 15.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 4 leaves, calendar inside back board (Box 9, Volume 114)
- [Sketchbook] 72: ITALY May 15 1997 to May 25 Venice and Beyond, 1997 May; Sketchbook No. 72; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 15.5. Three-quarters of leaves filled. Notes on final leaves and inside back board (Box 9, Volume 115)
- [Sketchbook] 73: India ! 11/5/97 (return Nov. 27 -'97 Thanksgiving), 1997 Nov.; Sketchbook No. 73; 80 leaves: pencil and watercolor, 10.7 x 15.5. Leaves two-thirds filled. Notes on final 4 leaves, calendar on final leaf, notes inside back board (Box 9, Volume 116)
- [Sketchbook], 1998 May 28; Sketchbook No. 115; 1 v.: pencil & pencil & watercolor, 10.5x15.5. Leaves three-quarters filled. (Box 9, Volume 117)
- [Sketchbook] August 1998 Montana sketch bk: Montana, 1998 Aug. 20; 1 v.: pencil & watercolor, 16 x 15. Leaves filled. (Box 9, Volume 118)
- [Sketchbook], 1999 Feb. 19-20; Sketchbook No. 116; 1 v.: pencil & pencil and watercolor, 10.5x15.5. Leaves half filled. (Box 9, Volume 119)
- [Sketchbook], 1999 March; Sketchbook No. 117; 1 v.: pencil & pencil and watercolor, 10.5x15.5. Leaves three-quarter filled. (Box 9, Volume 120)